mindmup.com 2018-06-16

# MindMup Privacy Policy

## MindMup Privacy Policy

`Document updated 22 April 2018`

MindMup for is an online mindmapping service. It allows users to quickly create mind maps, store them in the cloud and access from anywhere, collaborate and share mindmaps with colleagues and friends.

This Privacy Policy describes how and when MindMup collects, uses and shares your information when you use our services. When you use MindMup, you agree to the collection, transfer, manipulation, storage and other uses of your information as described in this Privacy Policy.

If you are looking for information related to the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), check out our GDPR page.

If you have any questions about this policy, please contact us.

This first section ( _Information collection and use_ ) describes how MindMup works isolated from third parties and optional services. The second section, _Information sharing_ , describes how we share information with third parties. The third section _Optional services_ describes how information is used by additional MindMup services.

## Information collection and use

Free users saving maps to MindMup storage: When you save maps to free MindMup storage, without authentication, we do not collect or store any personal information. The map content usage is subject to the MindMup Terms of Service

Third-party authentication: When you authenticate using a third party, such as Google Apps/GSuite, that service authenticates you directly, and an authentication token identifying you as the document owner is stored in your local browser session profile. This information is automatically discarded once you close the current browser session. MindMup also keeps a record of your third-party authentication metadata for auditing and security purposes. For detailed information on the data we store and process, check out check out our GDPR page.

MindMup Gold Storage: Content saved using MindMup Gold Storage is subject to the MindMup Gold Terms of Service

Registration: When you register for a MindMup Gold account, we collect and store your e-mail for authentication and billing purposes. We store this information using the Amazon Web Services platform. This information is automatically discarded six months after your subscription expires. To remove this information sooner, please contact us.

Cookies: We may use cookies to identify users that previously visited our web sites, for the purpose of analytics and selecting relevant news updates to display. You can clear this information at any time by clearing the browser cookies associated with mindmup.com domain.

## Information sharing

Saving to Google Drive: When you work with a mind map map stored on Google Drive, your browser directly interacts with that service and the map content never passes through our servers. We use standard Google Drive sharing functionality when you decide to share the map, and standard Google Drive authentication/authorization mechanisms for access control.

Using Google Photos: When you request to upload images from MindMup to Google Photos, your current authentication token is sent encrypted from the browser session to the MindMup image upload services running on the Amazon Web Services platform. This information is never stored and discarded instantly after the upload completes.

Analytics: We use analytics extensively for troubleshooting and optimisation purposes. We may record anonymous summary information about actions users perform including the type of action performed, but not the actual textual contents of any changes of changes. (So for example, we may record that you created a new map, but never about what you put into the map). This content is stored using the Amazon Web Services platform.

Payments: We use a third-party payment processor, [Stripe](https://stripe.com/). When you submit a payment to MindMup, your payment information data is communicated directly from your browser to Stripe, using HTTPS. We do not store your payment instrument details (such as card numbers), Stripe stores it securely for MindMup.

Information hosting: MindMup uses the Amazon Web Services platform for hosting web sites, application data and services. Any information you submit directly to us may be stored and processed using Amazon Web Services. This data is protected using standard Amazon Web Services account protection mechanisms.

E-mail: MindMup uses Google Mail e-mail services. Any e-mails you send to us will be processed and stored using Google Mail.

## Optional/additional services

Publishing Maps: MindMup allows users to publish maps online using MindMup Atlas. We never publish any information about your maps without your explicit request to publish the content. When you choose to publish a map, regardless of where it was originally stored, MindMup will upload the map contents to Amazon Web Services and make it public. Any maps published to Atlas are subject to MindMup Atlas terms of Service.

Exporting Maps: MindMup allows users to export maps into various content formats such as PDF, PNG and Google Writer. We do not share any contents about your maps without your explicit request to convert the map into a different format, and where remote services are required for conversion, we will warn you first about the map being uploaded remotely. Maps are sent to Amazon Web Services for processing, using HTTPS, and the converted format is kept on the Amazon S3 storage for up to 24 hours so you can retrieve and share it, protected by Amazon S3 authorization mechanisms. This data is automatically discarded after 24 hours. For more technical information on this, see Key information about data security.

## Changes to this Policy

We may revise this Privacy Policy from time to time. The most current version of the Terms will govern our use the Services and will always be at https://www.mindmup.com/resources/privacy_policy.html.

We will notify you about significant updates to this policy at <https://www.mindmup.com/news>. By continuing to access or use the Services after those changes become effective, you agree to be bound by the revised Privacy Policy.

If you disagree with this policy, you can stop using MindMup at any point and cancel your Gold account. Your data will automatically be removed from our services six months after your subscription expires. If you would like us to remove it sooner, please contact us.
